Guide to the Papers of Alice Virginia Keliher 1918-1995 MC 139
New York University Archives
Alice Keliher Papers
1918-1995
MC 139
New York University Archives
25.0 linear feet
Alice V. Keliher was born in Washington, D.C., in 1903 and was a scholar and expert in early school education. She taught at NYU from 1936 to 1960 and later at Wheelock College in Boston. She was also a close friend and neighbor of Eleanor Roosevelt, with whom she shared a concern for human rights issues. The collection includes articles, correspondence and personal memorabilia relating to her life and work in child education and development.
Keliher, Alice Virginia, 1903-
Provenance
This collection was transferred to the New York University Archives in 1995 by the estate of Alice Keliher.
Access Restrictions
Institutional records of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation (the date on which each document was written). Board of Trustees records are similarly closed for 35 years from the date of creation. The opening date for files spanning several years will be 20 years from the most recent date. Access will be given to material already 20 years old contained within a collection that is not yet open when such material can be isolated from the rest of the collection. Materials related to personnel, faculty grievances, job searches and all files with information that falls under the University's Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) policy are permanently restricted. Please contact the University Archivists with specific questions regarding restrictions.
Additionally, the audiovisual materials in the collection have not all been converted to a digital format. Please contact the Archives with specific requests for access to these materials.
This collection is in
off-site storage
.
Biographical Note
Alice V. Keliher was born in Washington, D.C., in 1903. She received Bachelor's, Master's and Doctoral degrees in three years at Teachers College at Columbia University. She then began work with Dr. Gesell at Yale in 1930. She emerged as an expert on early school education, teaching at NYU from 1936 to 1960. An active scholar, she attended virtually every conference on childhood education around the country through the 1940s and 1950s. During WWII, she helped shape the day care system as director of child and youth services of the New York Office of Civilian Defense and secretary of Mayor La Guardia's Committee on the Wartime Care of Children. In addition, she was a close friend and neighbor of Eleanor Roosevelt, with whom she shared a concern for human rights issues. In 1960 she left NYU and went to Wheelock College in Boston, where she became the Massachusetts regional training officer for Head Start, the federal program designed to ameliorate disadvantaged childrens' education.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains Keliher's personal and professional papers from 1918 to 1995. Professional materials include the National Society for Education Yearbooks (1972-1995), books authored by educators, contributions to Columbia University Teachers College Education Series (1925-1946), articles written by Keliher, extensive correspondence with educators and other scholars, research materials, correspondence with the House Committee on Un-American Activities, photos, and clippings. Personal materials include correspondence with Eleanor Roosevelt and Anna Freud, scrapbooks and photo albums with images of India, Ireland, Guam, Belgium, family and friends.
This collection also includes all of Keliher's printed articles and books and two unfinished and unpublished book projects: one on her life and that of the educators that shaped her thought (Box 16); and another one titled "Children at School," on child development and the elementary school program (Box 13).
There is information on every school and institution she was involved with, films, photos, slides and tape recordings of seminars, conferences and trips. Please note that audiovisual materials may need to be converted to a digital format for viewing; please contact the University Archives with questions about whether these materials are currently available. There exists also personal memorabilia, such as trophies and honorary degrees. Also included are personal letters and published materials by and about prominent educators of the time, including Lawrence Frank, John Dewey, William Kilpatrick, and Arnold Gesell.
Arrangement
Folders are generally arranged chronologically or alphabetically, depending on the nature of the series. Where there are no folder numbers listed, materials are stored unfoldered in boxes (items such as books, tapes, memorabilia).
The collection is organized into 4 series:
Printed Material
Personal publications and files
Work-related correspondence and other files
Personal memorabilia
Related Material at the New York University Archives
University Archives Biographical Files, "Keliher, Alice, 1903-1995"
University Archives Portrait Files, "Keliher, Alice"
Columbia University Teachers College; Freud, Anna, 1895-; Gesell, Arnold, 1880-1961.; Keliher, Alice Virginia, 1903-; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947.; New York State Committee on the Care of Children in Wartime; New York State Department of Children and Youth Services; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.;; United States Congress House Committee on Un-American Activities; Wheelock College; Clippings; Correspondence; Early childhood education; Headstart programs; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Yearbooks
- Series I: Printed Material
  Scope and Contents note
  Mostbooks are related to education. They are not ordered alphabetically. There is an extensivecollection of books by John Dewey, Arnold Gesell, Lawrence K. Frank and William HeardKirkpatrick.
  - Subseries A: National Society forEducation Yearbooks
    Arranged chronologically,1972-1995.
    - Early Childhood Education, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General note
      bar code#: 3 1142 04058099 8
    - The Courts and Education, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Education and the Brain, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Gifted and the Talented, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Classroom Management, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Learning a Second Language, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Toward Adolescence: The Middle School Years, 1980 (Box 1)
    - The Social Studies, 1981 (Box 1)
    - Policy Making in Education, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Education and Work, 1982 (Box 1)
    - Staff Development, 1983 (Box 1)
    - The Humanities in Precollegiate Education, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Education in School and Nonschool Settings, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Society as Educator in an Age of Transition, 1987 (Box 1)
    - The Ecology of School Renewal, 1987 (Box 1)
    - Critical Issues in Curriculum, 1988 (Box 2)
      bar code#: 3 1142 04058100 4
    - Cultural Literacy and the Idea of General Education, 1988 (Box 2)
    - The Teacher as Text and the Text as Teacher, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Schooling and Disability, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Textbooks and Schooling in the United States, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Educational Leadership and Changing Contexts, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Educational Leadership and Changing Contexts, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Care and Education of America's Young Children, 1991 (Box 2)
    - Evaluation and Education: At Quarter Century, 1991 (Box 2)
    - The Changing Contexts of Teaching, 1992 (Box 2)
    - The Arts, Education, and Aesthetic Knowing, 1992 (Box 2)
    - Gender and Education, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Bilingual Education: Politics, Practice and Research, 1993 (Box 2)
    - Teacher Research and Educational Reform, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Bloom's Taxonomy: A Forty-Year Retrospective, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Creating New Educational Communities, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Changing Populations/Changing Schools, 1995 (Box 2)
  - Subseries B: Books
    Kept inoriginal order, not alphabetically.
    - Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development. Perceiving, Behaving, Becoming: A New Focus., 1962 (Box 2)
    - Central High School, Washington, D.C. The Brecky, Yearbook of the Classes of 1918., undated (Box 2)
    - Isaacs, Susan M.A., D.SC. The Nursery Years., undated (Box 2)
    - Toffler, Alvin. Learning for Tomorrow., 1974 (Box 2)
    - Washburne and Marland, Jr. Winnetka. The History and Significance of an Educational Experiment., 1963 (Box 2)
    - Kozol, Jonathan. Free Schools., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Frank,Lawrence, K. On the Importance of Infancy., 1966 (Box 2)
    - McDonald, Ben F. Jr. The Darker Side of Childhood., 1974 (Box 2)
    - American Association of School Administrators. Christopher Jencks in Perspective., 1973 (Box 3)
      bar code#: 3 1142 04058101 2
    - Dodge, Grace H. A Brief Sketch of the Early History of Teachers College., 1980 (Box 3)
    - Teachers College Bulletin. Selected Readings from the Teachers College Record., 1982 (Box 3)
    - Teachers College Bulletin. Selected Readings from the Teachers College Record., 1984 (Box 3)
    - Royal Readers, No. III., 1929 (Box 3)
    - Nelson and Linton. Patterns of Poser: Social Foundations of Education., 1968 (Box 3)
    - Rowen, Betty. The Children We See., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Fein and Clarke-Stewart. Day Care in Context., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Citizen's Committee on Children of New York City, Inc. Children Absent from School., 1949 (Box 3)
    - Spodek, Bernard. Early Childhood Education., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Freud, Anna. Normality and Pathology in Childhood., 1966 (Box 3)
    - MacCracken, Mary. A Circle of Children., 1973 (Box 3)
    - Frank, Mary and Frank, Lawrence K. How to Help Your Child in School., 1954 (Box 3)
    - Wiles, Kimball. Teaching for Better Schools., 1952 (Box 3)
    - Strecker, Edward A., M.D. TheirMothers' Sons., 1946 (Box 3)
    - Hymes, James L. Jr. A Child Development Point of View., 1955 (Box 3)
    - Boyd, William. The Emile of Jean Jacques Rousseau., 1962 (Box 3)
    - Eliot, Godfrey. Film and Education., 1948 (Box 4)
      bar code#: 3 1142 04058102 0
    - Embree and Waxman. Investment in People., 1949 (Box 4)
    - Bergmann, Thesi and Freud, Anna. Children in the Hospital., 1965 (Box 4)
    - Freud, Anna. The Ego and the Mechanisms of Defense., 1946 (Box 4)
    - Coles, Robert. Children of Crisis., 1964 (Box 4)
    - Van Waters, Miriam, Ph.D. Youth in Conflict., 1926 (Box 4)
    - Los Angeles County Superintendent of Schools Office. Guiding Today's Youth., 1961 (Box 4)
    - Keister, Mary Elizabeth. Discipline., 1973 (Box 4)
    - AASA. Curriculum Handbook for School Executives., 1973 (Box 4)
    - Brewer-Landy. Occupations Today., 1949 (Box 4)
    - Duberman, Martin. Black Mountain., 1973 (Box 4)
    - Chisholm, G.B. Prescription for Survival., 1957 (Box 4)
    - Hymes, James L., Jr. Twenty Years in Review. A look at 1971-1990 (Box 4)
    - Teachers College Bulletin. Selected Readings from the Teachers College Record., 1982 (Box 4)
    - Teachers College Bulletin. Selected Readings from the Teachers College Record., 1983 (Box 4)
    - Riesman, David. The Lonely Crowd., 1961 (Box 4)
    - Kelley, Earl C. In Defense of Youth., 1962 (Box 4)
    - The Save the Children Fund Post War Committee. Children in Bondage., 1942 (Box 4)
    - Stone, James C. and Schneider, Frederick W. Readings in the Foundations of Education. Commitment to Teaching,Volume II., 1965 (Box 4)
    - Readings in the Foundations of Education. Commitment to Teaching, Volume II., 1965 (Box 4)
    - Kelley, Earl C. Education for What is Real., 1947 (Box 4)
    - Woodsworth, Robert Sessions. Dynamic Psychology., 1925 (Box 4)
    - Devries, Rheta and Kohlberg, Lawrence. Constructivist Early Education: Overview and Comparison with Other Programs., 1987 (Box 5)
      bar code#: 3 1142 04058103 8
    - Ryan, Carson W. Mental healththrough Education., 1938 (Box 5)
    - Olson, Willard C. Child Development., 1959 (Box 5)
    - Wiles,Kimball. Supervision for Better Schools., 1950 (Box 5)
    - Davis Hurley, Beatrice. Curriculum for Elementary SchoolChildren., 1957 (Box 5)
    - Murphy, Gardner. Human Potentialities., 1958 (Box 5)
    - Barr, Donald. Who Pushed Humpty Dumpty?, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Katz,Lilian G. Current Topics in Early Childhood Education, Vol. 1., 1971 (Box 5)
    - Thayer, V.T. The Role of the School in AmericanSociety., 1962 (Box 5)
    - Georgia Assoc. of Curriculum and Instructional Supervision. Instructional Supervision in Georgia., 1925 (Box 5)
    - Torrance, Paul E. Guiding Creative Talent., 1962 (Box 5)
    - Melby, Ernest O. The Teacher and Learning., 1963 (Box 5)
    - Wright, Lula E. A First Graduate Work., 1932 (Box 5)
    - Childs, John L. Ph.D. Education and the Philosophy of Experimentalism., 1931 (Box 5)
    - Johnson, Harriet M. Children in the Nursery School., 1928 (Box 5)
    - Kelley, Earl C. and Rasey, Marie I. Education and the Nature of Man., 1952 (Box 5)
  - Subseries C: Teachers College.Contributions to Education Series (1925-1946) and other books
    - Betzner, Jean, Ph.D. Content and Form of Original Compositions Dictated by Children from Five to Eight Years of Age., 1930 (Box 6)
      bar code#: 3 1142 04058104 6
    - McGinnis, William C., PhD. School Administrative and Supervisory Organizations in Cities of 20,000 to 50,000Population., 1929 (Box 6)
    - Schwesinger, Gladys Clotilde, PhD. The Social-Ethical Significance of Vocabulary., 1926 (Box 6)
    - Crabbs, Lelah Mae, Ph.D. Measuring Efficiency in Supervision and Teaching., 1925 (Box 6)
    - Gans, Roma, Ph.D. A Study of Critical Reading Comprehension in the Intermediate Grades., 1940 (Box 6)
    - Allard, Lucille, PhD. A Study of the Leisure Activities of Certain Elementary School Teachers of Long Island., 1939 (Box 6)
    - Zirbes, Laura, PhD. Comparative Studies of Current Practice in Reading., 1928 (Box 6)
    - Unzicker, Cecilia E. PhD. An Experimental Study of the Effect of the Use of the Typewriter on Beginning Reading., 1934 (Box 6)
    - Sauvain, Walter Howard, PhD. A Study of the Opinions of Certain Professional and Non-Professional Groups Regarding Homogeneous and Ability Grouping., 1934 (Box 6)
    - Adams, Fay, Ph.D. The Initiation of an Activity Program into a Public School., 1934 (Box 6)
    - Frawley, Honora Margaret, Ph.D. Certain Procedures of Studying Poetry in the Fifth Grade., 1932 (Box 6)
    - Burr, Marvin Y., Ph.D. A Study of Homogeneous Grouping., 1931 (Box 6)
    - Broady, Knute O. School Provision for Individual Differences; Apr-05., 1930 (Box 6)
    - Labrant, Lou L. and Heller, Frieda M. An Evaluation of Free Reading in Grades Seven to Twelve, Inclusive., undated (Box 6)
    - Palmer, Richard. School Broadcasting in Britain., 1947 (Box 6)
    - Thompson, Rose. Hush, Child!Can't You Hear the Music?., 1982 (Box 6)
    - Redl, Fritz. When We Deal with Children., 1966 (Box 6)
    - Alexander and Parker. The New Education in the German Republic., 1929 (Box 6)
    - Benedict, Agnes E. and Franklin Adele. Your Best Friends are Your Children, 1951 (Box 6)
    - Ginsburg, Ethel L. Public Health is People., 1950 (Box 6)
    - Larrick, Nancy. A Parent's Guide to Children's Education., 1963 (Box 6)
    - Smith, Cressman and Speer. Education and Society., 1942 (Box 6)
    - Powell, Douglas R. Families and Early Childhood Programs., 1989 (Box 6)
    - Larrick, Nancy. See for Yourself, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Fedder, Ruth. The Troubled Child Can Learn., 1979 (Box 6)
    - Perrin Berson, Minne. Kindergarten., 1959 (Box 7)
      bar code#: 3 1142 04058105 3
    - Bureau for Intercultural Education. Social Perceptions and Attitudes of Children., 1949 (Box 7)
    - Lane, Bess B. Your Part in Your Child's Education., 1948 (Box 7)
    - Katz, Evangelou and Hartman. The Case for Mixed Age Grouping in Early Education., 1990 (Box 7)
    - Kamii, Constance, editor. Achievement Testing in the Early Grades: the Games Grown-Ups Play., 1990 (Box 7)
    - Sorley Walker, Katherine and Butler, Joan. Ballet for Boys and Girls., 1979 (Box 7)
    - Parker, Lockie. Art and People., 1934 (Box 7)
    - Larrick, Nancy. A Parent's Guide to Children's Reading., 1958 (Box 7)
    - Mearns, Hughes. Creative Power: The Education of Youth in the Creative Arts., 1929 (Box 7)
    - Weiss, Jerry M. Reading in the Secondary Schools., 1961 (Box 7)
    - Quayle, Nancy. Sunday to Sunday with the "Under Fives"., 1948 (Box 7)
    - Harvard Educational Review. The Rights of Children, Series No. 9., 1974 (Box 7)
    - Burlingham, Dorothy. Twins., 1952 (Box 7)
    - Edwards Tietje, Grace. A Study Evaluating Spontaneous Dramatic Activities of Kindergarten Children., 1933 (Box 7)
    - Hale Woodruff. 50 Years of His Art., 1979 (Box 7)
    - Bowlby, J. Maternal Care and Mental Health., 1952 (Box 7)
    - Adams-Jeremiah, Dorothy. Pace Pattern and Pitch., 1963 (Box 7)
    - Wall, Schonell and Olson. Failure in School., 1962 (Box 7)
    - Kontos, Susan. Family Day Care: Out of the Shadows and into the Limelight., 1992 (Box 7)
    - Florida State University. Education in Florida Past and Present., 1954 (Box 7)
    - Ellison, Alfred. Music with Children., 1959 (Box 7)
    - Herrick and Jacobs. Children and the Language Arts., 1955 (Box 7)
    - Steinhauer, Lillian R. Poems., 1961 (Box 7)
    - Lipton and Provence. Infants in Institutions., 1962 (Box 7)
    - Leshan, Eda J. The Conspiracy Against Childhood., 1967 (Box 7)
    - Goddard, Nora L. Reading in the Modern Infants' School., 1958 (Box 7)
    - Hymes, Jr. James L. A Child Development Point of View., 1955 (Box 7)
    - Jones, Elizabeth, editor. Growing Teachers: Partnerships in Staff Development., 1993 (Box 7)
    - Boyer, Ernest L. Ready to Learn., 1992 (Box 7)
    - Saran, Mary. For Community Service, The Mount Carmel Experiment., 1974 (Box 7)
    - The Public Papers and Addresses of Franklin D. Roosevelt. Compiled by Samuel I. Rosenman, 4 volumes, undated (Box 8)
      bar code#: 3 1142 04058106 1
    - Volume I: The Call to Battle Stations., 1941 (Box 8)
    - Volume II: Humanity on the Defensive., 1942 (Box 8)
    - Volume III: The Tide Turns., 1943 (Box 8)
    - Volume IV: Victory and the Threshold of Peace., 1944-1945 (Box 8)
    - Fleming, Robert S. Curriculum for Today's Boys and Girls., 1963 (Box 8)
    - Andrews, Saurborn and Schneider. Physical Education for Today's Boys and Girls., 1960 (Box 8)
    - Goffin, Stacie G. and Stegelin, Dolores A. Changing Kindergartens., 1992 (Box 8)
    - Valley Manor Retirement Apartments. In a Manor of Speaking; July, 1995. (Box 8)
    - Lane, Howard. On Educating Human Beings., 1964 (Box 8)
    - Unwin, Nora S. The Chickadees Come and other Poems., 1977 (Box 8)
    - Curry, Nancy E. and Johnson, Carl N. Beyond Self-Esteem., 1986 (Box 8)
    - McLeod, K. June. A Follow-Up Study of Graduates of the Fifth-Year Program of Teacher Education at NYU. AVK, Project Chairman., 1952-1953 (Box 8)
    - Federal Security Agency. Social Security Administration, Children's Bureau Publication, Number 324. Your Child from 6-12., 1949 (Box 8)
    - Yale-Fairfield Study of Elementary Teaching. Report., 1954-1955 (Box 8)
    - Yale-Fairfield Study of Elementary Teaching. Teacher Preparation for Mothers who are College Graduates; Sept., 1959. (Box 8)
    - Yale-Fairfield Study of Elementary Teaching. Teacher Assistants., 1959 (Box 8)
    - Damon, S. Foster. Amy Lowell, A Chronicle with Extracts from her Correspondence., 1935 (Box 8)
    - Gardner, D.E.M. Experiment and Tradition in Primary Schools., 1966 (Box 8)
    - Commission on Teacher Education. Helping Teachers Understand Children., 1945 (Box 8)
    - United States Department of Labor, Children's Bureau Publication No. 266. Proceedings of the White House Conference on Children in a Democracy; Jan. 18-20, 1940. (Box 8)
    - Parker, Beryl. The Austrian Educational Institutes., 1936 (Box 8)
    - Archambault, Reginald D. Dewey on Education, Appraisals., 1966 (Box 9)
      bar code#: 3 1142 04058107 9
    - Dewey, John. Art as Experience., 1934 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John and Tufts, James H. Ethics., 1929 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. Democracy and Education., 1966 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. The Sources of a Science of Education., 1929 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. Recollections by Robert Bruce Williams., 1981 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. Reconstruction in Philosophy., 1962 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, Kilpatrick, Bode, Childs, Raup, Hullfish, and Thayer. The Educational Frontier., 1933 (Box 9)
    - Handlin, Oscar. John Dewey's Challenge to Education., 1959 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. Teachers College Bulletin. A Reprint of Three Articles: "The Psychology of Drawing," "Imagination" and Expression, Culture,and Industry in Education, 1919 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. Education and the Social Order., 1936 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. My Pedagogic Creed, 1897 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. Education and our Present Social Problems., 1933 (Box 9)
    - Frank, Lawrence K. and Mary. Your Adolescent at Home and in School., 1956 (Box 9)
    - Frank, Lawrence K. The School as Agent for Cultural Renewal., 1960 (Box 9)
    - Frank, Lawrence K. Conserving Human Resources in the Field of Early Childhood: An Address given at Macy Foundation, New York, NY before The National Council of Childhood Education., 1941 (Box 9)
    - Associates of Bank Street College of Education (incl. Frank)"Imagination in Education," Conference., 1956 (Box 9)
    - Gesell, Arnold. The Pre-School Child., 1923 (Box 9)
    - Kilpatrick, William Heard. Our Educational Task., 1930 (Box 9)
    - Kilpatrick, William Heard. Source Book in the Philosophy of Education., 1926 (Box 9)
    - Squire, James R. A New Look at Progressive Education., 1972 (Box 9)
    - National Congress of Parents and Teachers, Proceedings., 1939 (Box 9)
    - Goldsmith, Cornelia. Better Day Care for the Young Child., 1972 (Box 9)
    - Committee on Education and Labor House of Representatives. Comprehensive Preschool Education and Child Day-Care Act of 1969. (Box 9)
    - Widmer, Emmy Louise. The Critical Years: Early Childhood Education at the Crossroads., 1970 (Box 9)
    - Davis, Allison. Social-Class Influences upon Learning., 1948 (Box 9)
    - Aikin, Wilford M. The Story of the Eight-Year Study., 1942 (Box 9)
    - Crativity iz a Hell of a Lot of Fun!(Student-Made Book); Summer, 1964. (Box 9)
    - Kearney, Nolan C. Elementary School Objectives: A Report Prepared for the Mid-Century Committee on Outcomes in Elementary Education., undated (Box 9)
    - Rt. Hon. Arthur Greenwood. "All Children are Mine" inaugural Margaret McMillan Lecture., 1952 (Box 9)
    - Lord, Miriam. Margaret McMillan in Bradford with Reminiscences., 1956 (Box 9)
    - Hershey, John. Intelligence,Choice,and Consent., 1959 (Box 9)
    - The Second Multiprofessional Conference on Children Under Six: Crucial Issues in Education for Today's World. Who Should Teach Young Children?., 1965 (Box 9)
    - Western Arts Association Bulletin. Yearbook Issue Containing the Report of the 1956 Convention Program Based on the Theme: "How Creative are You?" (Box 9)
    - A. C. E. I.(Association for Childhood Ed. International) Readings from Childhood Education. Articles of Lasting Value. Includes articles by Avk, Kilpatrick, Gessell, Biber, Zirbes, etc., 1966 (Box 9)
    - Frost,Joe L. Issues and Innovations in the Teaching of Reading., 1967 (Box 9)
    - Whiteside Taylor, Katharine. Do Adolescents Need Parents?., 1938 (Box 9)
    - Wilson, Charles G. Healthful School Living., 1957 (Box 9)
    - Raubinger, Frederick M. and Rowe, Harold G. The Individual and Education, Some Contemporary Issues., 1968 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, John. Human Nature and Conduct., 1922 (Box 9)
    - Dewey, Evelyn and Glover, Katherine, 1934 (Box 9)
    - Cremin, Lawrence A. The Transformation of the School., 1961 (Box 9)
    - Kilpatrick, William Heard. Philosophy of Education., 1951 (Box 9)
    - Kilpatrick, William Heard. Foundations of Method., 1926 (Box 9)
    - Camp Mayhew, Katherine and Camp Edwards, Anna. The Dewey School., 1936 (Box 9)